

Scan to see

Rahmat Saputra

Software Engineer

Menteng, South Jakarta | rahmatsaputra.my.id@gmail.com | +62 812 1019 7870 | https://www.rahmatsaputra.my.id/

SUMMARY

I love working with website and android app project especially as a front end developer or ui designer. One of my experiences as a front end developer are working with React Native to integrating android and web project with APIs, optimizing project using design pattern, state management, until test driven development to deliver exceptional customer experiences. I am a self motivated person, passionate to learn, and good team player, also have positive attitude.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT Telekomunikasi Selular

Mei 2020 - Present

React Native Developer at MyOrbit App & Website (https://www.myorbit.id) Project

- Blog page design implementation from zeplin to myorbit website
- Developing website filtering feature at myorbit app
- Telkomsel point design implementation from zeplin to app feature
- Create and design implementation microsite from zeplin to website as a campaign purpose
- Integrating link download invoice and tutorial at myorbit website as well as app
- Development A/B testing product, promo, remove add on, deals, instalment page at myorbit website
- Brand guideline, secure payment badge design implementation from zeplin to website feature
- Implementation insider GTM and user consent at myorbit website
- Creating telkom employee racing program and sales force help desk as a landing page from zeplin
- New design implementation on logout, change language, lucky draw feature from figma to myorbit app
- Implementation tracker firebase analytic at myorbit app
- Success preorder, pickup point, disney+, bulk purchase, invoice, info promo, vocher co-brand, o2o package delivered, success purchase design implementation from zeplin to email
- News deals, calculator quota, modem and product selection indibox, home, feature, digipos delivery tracking, digipos help center, product page design implementation from zeplin to website page
- New design implementation on splash, onboarding, change ssid, notification (info, promo, transaction), profile, history transacation, dashboard, mega menu, feedback, pairing, find account, etalase product, dynamic modem password, factory reset, help, coachmark, forget password screen from figma to myorbit app

PT Bank Mandiri Februari 2020 - Mei 2020

Android Developer at EPro Android Application Project

- Implementation MVP design pattern using java programming language
- Integrating with APIs from backend using retrofit and httpclient library
- Design dashboard, implementation from marvel to screen EPro app

PT BRAVASS November 2019 - Februari 2020

Front End Developer at Bravaas Website Internal Project

- Creating and developeing admin, room, periode, member, invoice page at bravass web
- Integrating bravass web with APIs from backend, to get feature search, add, update, delete data until logout account at bravass web using polymer framework.

Tax Center - Gunadarma University

November 2017 - November 2019

Programmer at Tax Center Web Project

- Maintaning feature website tax centre official at https://taxcenter.gunadarma.ac.id
- Maintaning content website brevet a&b at http://taxcenter.gunadarma.ac.id/kursus/
- Creating test levelling website with moodle for tax volunteer event recruitment

VOLUNTEER

RELAWAN PAJAK KANWIL - DJP JAWA BARAT III

Agustus 2019

Logistic Division

- Ensure all event equipment is functioning properly
- Ensure that the sequence of events is in accordance with the specified
- Work in a team, agile, and ready to respond in the field

RELAWAN PAJAK TAX CENTER - GUNADARMA UNIVERSITY

Februari 2019

Assitant Division

- Assisting taxpayers in fulfilling annual tax reporting in accordance with the data held by each taxpayer
- Assisting taxpayers to get electronic filing identification number obtained from the directorate general of taxes
- Assisting taxpayers in filling out forms 1770, 1770s, 1770ss according to the reporting steps

EDUCATION

INFORMATION ENGINEERING - GUNADARMA UNIVERSITY

April 2015 - Oktober 2019

- Head of class on campus in the department of informatics engineering
- Laboratory assistant at tax center gunadarma university
- Exam supervisor at the Brevet A & B test held by the tax center
- Member of information technology association (HIMTI)

ADDITIONAL

Skills: Java(Native) with design pattern (MVP, MVC) and state management (RxJava), HTML/CSS/SCSS with storage (Local Storage, Session Storage), Dart(Flutter) with design pattern (MVVM) and state management (BLoC, RxDart), Javascript(React Native, React JS, Typescript, Polymer) with state management (Redux) and test driven development (Jest), SQL Database (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle), PHP (Laravel, Code Igniter, Slim, Lumen) with design pattern (MVC,MVP), Microsoft Office (Ms. Word, Ms. Excel, Ms. Power Point), Microsoft Teams, Design Graphic (Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Zeplin, Blender), Google Marketing Platform (Google Analytic, Google Tag Manager, Google Optimize), Google Workspace, Insider for Website, Firebase Analytic, Postman, XCode, Visual Studio Code, React Native Debugger, GitLab, Github, Android Studio, SmartGIT, JIRA (Software, Confluence), Trello, Moesif Origin & CORS Changer, CMS(Wordpress, Pimcore, Blogger)

Languages: indonesia (native proficiency from indonesia), english (quite good at listening, speaking, and pronunciation)

Certifications, Training, Course, Achievement: Gunadarma University Course (Java Programming Language Fundamental, Web Programming Fundamental, Desktop Programming Fundamental, J2EE For Beginner, Java Programming For Intermediate, J2EE For Intermediate, Java Programming Project), BitDegree Course (Interactive Coding For Beginners: What is CSS, HTML, & Web Development), Dicoding Course (Learn to Make Android Apps For Beginners, Start Programming with Darts, Start Programming with Kotlin), Educba Course (Java 8 Programming Tutorials), Eduonix Course (Ultimate Java Development), Seminar Attendance Certificate by Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Informatika (Prepare Your Self Into The Future), Tax National Seminar Attendance Certificate by Kanwil Directorate General of Taxes III (Potential Taxes and Enforcement of Justice on Ecommerce Transactions), Seminar Attendance Certificate by Laboratorium Teknik Informatika (Seminar e-Public Service: Smart City), Project Completion Certification by Indonesia Android Kejar Batch 3 (Android Basic: User Interface & User Input), LinkedIn Course (Learning Spring with Spring Boot, Advanced SQL for Query Tuning and Performance Optimization), SoloLearn Course (Java Tutorial, SQL Fundamentals), Public Test Certification by TestDome (Android - Ranking in the top 25%, SQL - Ranking in the top 10%), Udemy Course (Java 10 Tutorials), Diploma Equivalent to Baccalaureate Degree Majoring in Informatics Engineering by Gunadarma University, Bachelor's Degree with A Major in Information Technology by Gunadarma University.

Enthusiast: Ui Designer(Figma, Marvel, Adobe XD, Zeplin), Front End Developer(React Native, Flutter, Android Java)